<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-12-07T15:00:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jfy’s Website</title><subtitle>Jeff Feiwell's personal website</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Maxims for (Startup) Investmenting</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/notes/2020/12/07/investing-thesis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Maxims for (Startup) Investmenting" /><published>2020-12-07T10:41:39-05:00</published><updated>2020-12-07T10:41:39-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/notes/2020/12/07/investing-thesis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/notes/2020/12/07/investing-thesis.html">&lt;p&gt;All else being equal, the team with the better distribution strategy will win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All else being equal, the team that ruthlessly executes (vs the competition) long term will win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Financing is a function of the business model. The arguments over raising vs bootstrapping are akin to debating whether to take a car or airplane, it’s entirely dependent on where you’re going and when you need to get there. Opendoor needed a lot of cash to get off the ground, Instagram didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The founder(s) has conviction in their vision of the future, and knows which direction leads there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The founder(s) can articulate that vision and business in almost offensively simple terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The employees can articulate the &lt;em&gt;same&lt;/em&gt; vision and business in almost offensively simple terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The founder(s) must be magnets for talent. OR in extreme cases, excellent coaches. This is almost always an AND.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The founder(s) are both ruthless &amp;amp; empathetic. Introspective &amp;amp; delusionally confident. Irreverent &amp;amp; observant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is founder(s) / market fit. Home Depot founders couldn’t build Pinterest &amp;amp; vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exception to founder quals is a product and corresponding model that require beating consumers away with a stick to halt growth. E.g. Slack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team exudes (positive) energy. Employees are pumped to be there. They’ve got the Mo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Business equation simplified to Dollars In =&amp;gt; Dollars Out. Roughly translates to unit economics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The growth strategy is predicated on an arbitrage the market is missing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company must have an Accumulating Advantage. Flywheel is nice but not required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brand matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Why Now makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most, if not all, mainstream commentators would scoff at the business and write it off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All businesses are created equal. Home Depot makes 6x more money than Netflix. Time horizons be damned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time horizons matter. Value creation matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Final rule…there are exceptions to every rule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finally, what’s wrong &amp;amp; what am I missing?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Note: These aren’t *necessarily* in order.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Notes" /><summary type="html">All else being equal, the team with the better distribution strategy will win.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Setting the Table</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/books/2020/10/21/meyer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Setting the Table" /><published>2020-10-21T11:41:39-04:00</published><updated>2020-10-21T11:41:39-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/books/2020/10/21/meyer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/books/2020/10/21/meyer.html">&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/font-awesome/4.7.0/css/font-awesome.min.css&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight:500;font-style:italic;&quot;&gt; Author: Danny Meyer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;margin-top:15px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight:500;&quot;&gt;tl;dr:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;&lt;b&gt;Stars: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;fa fa-star checked&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;fa fa-star checked&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;fa fa-star checked&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;fa fa-star checked&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;fa fa-star&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amazon: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Setting-Table-Transforming-Hospitality-Business/dp/0060742763&quot;&gt;Setting the Table: The Transforming Power of Hospitality in Business&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Books" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Biggest Grift</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/essays/2020/10/13/the-biggest-grift.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Biggest Grift" /><published>2020-10-13T11:59:39-04:00</published><updated>2020-10-13T11:59:39-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/essays/2020/10/13/the-biggest-grift</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/essays/2020/10/13/the-biggest-grift.html">&lt;p&gt;Imagine this scenario. An old friend shows up asking for money. Though you don’t speak often, your history with that friend runs deep. They helped shape you as a person and you have incredibly fond memories of them. In fact you even paid them tens of thousands of dollars to help you along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, with hat in hand, they tell you they’re broke. Only, they’re not. You feel bad though, even if they are just short on cash. Plus, others could pass them by — which would be bad for the value of your association with them. So you give them some money and you both go on your way. Until they come back again. And again. And again. In fact, it turns out they’re asking every friend they ever had for cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you start digging. You find out that your friend actually has a borderline monopoly. They have a business generating hundreds of millions, even billions, in revenue. They lock in customers for 4 years a time, sell them goods at sky high markups, and without fail, have a never ending stream of new customers every year. They even charge their customers 150% for lunch. On top of that, they collude with their peers to increase prices every year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the deal gets even sweeter. They’ve arranged for the federal government to underwrite their customers, who can no longer afford their product, with virtually zero lending standards and no cap. The best part is that no matter what, they get their tax funded pass through cash, and their customers are stuck with the bill! They didn’t stop there, they’re so savvy they’ve arranged to pay no income tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point you are left scratching your head, why in the world does my friend need this cash? After all, they’ve got a great little operation going. So you search deeper, knowing something else has to be missing. And there it is, the golden nugget that makes the first racket seem like a lemonade stand — a hedge fund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your friend is running a multi billion dollar hedge fund. Holy smokes, and he’s asking &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt; for money!? Yes, of course he is. Because your friend, who was able to amass such an empire, tax free, is no dummy. Why would he ever build his new pool house and refurbish his third summer home with his own money when he can get it from you? If you pony up enough for him to build an olympic size pool too, he may even name it after you. What an honor!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you go to your friend’s business to solve this once and for all. You’re greeted by one stellar employee only to find 10 others sitting around pontificating. Man that one works hard. You can tell they have a material impact on your friend’s customers. That one is a real treasure to society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You ask your friend why he needs the extra employees and he explains that you are a rube who doesn’t understand the sophistication of his business. You press that they clearly offer no value to customers. He explains a byzentine system his company set up whereby any employee who works there long enough can’t be fired — no matter what. You point out half of them haven’t been there long, your issue with them is they’re pitching customers on products that have no value. Maybe even negative value. And wait a second, you’re charging them how much again? And the government is subsidizing this why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You ask your friend plainly — &lt;em&gt;you said&lt;/em&gt; you were broke, but you clearly just have cash flow problems — despite running the world’s greatest monopoly! You’re unwilling to make the obvious choice. The only choice. Tell me again, why do you need my money?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have clearly struck a nerve as your friend refuses to entertain such sophomoric inquiries. He asks you to leave. What about all our good times? You ask. Suddenly, the friend who so frantically needed your money, has no interest in speaking with you. So you leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years later your friend shows up again acting as if the whole episode didn’t happen. He needs to meet payroll and build a new state of the art ice skating rink…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/share?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; class=&quot;twitter-share-button&quot; data-show-count=&quot;false&quot;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Essays" /><summary type="html">Imagine this scenario. An old friend shows up asking for money. Though you don’t speak often, your history with that friend runs deep. They helped shape you as a person and you have incredibly fond memories of them. In fact you even paid them tens of thousands of dollars to help you along the way.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Now Buffering, Politics is Downstream from Distribution</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/essays/2020/09/20/now-buffering-politics-distribution.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Now Buffering, Politics is Downstream from Distribution" /><published>2020-09-20T11:59:39-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-20T11:59:39-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/essays/2020/09/20/now-buffering-politics-distribution</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/essays/2020/09/20/now-buffering-politics-distribution.html">&lt;p&gt;During Jackon’s Bank War in 1834, John Calhoun rose to the Senate floor to lament the fact Andrew Jackson had printed his own remarks to his Cabinet in Jackon’s newspaper the Washington Globe. Calhoun decried this as an exercise of despotic power, saying it “was clearly and manifestly intended as an appeal to the people of the United States, and opens a new and direct organ of communication between the President and them unknown to the Constitution and the laws…There are but two channels…through which the President can communicate with the people — by messages to the Two Houses of Congress…or by Proclamation.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jackson wasn’t the first President to operate a party organ from the White House, but he was the first populist President. He predicated his authority on the will of the people. Jackson successfully appealed directly to the people by both leveraging new technology and breaking conventional norms. Sound familiar?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The late Andrew Breitbart famously said that “politics is downstream of culture”. In today’s political environment, where everything from butter to basketball is politicized, that seems demonstrably true. But there’s a vital step in-between that’s often overlooked — distribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Politics — who we elect, the course of their actions, and the events surrounding how we govern ourselves — is downstream from distribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;//&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;American politics has manifested itself in different incarnations fitting both our circumstances and communications technologies. We even teach American history through this lens. We learn about Paul Revere’s midnight ride — alerting citizens by voice at the speed of horseback. We learn about FDR’s fireside chats, and how TV audiences preferred Kennedy but radio listeners thought Nixon won the 1960 debate. It is an intractable reality that the public reaction and decisions made following Kennedy’s assinsation would have been starkly different in both the party newspaper era and today’s social media climate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would we have invaded the USSR due to unrelenting social media speculation? Would one side string together &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wokal_distance/status/1298923653896130560&quot;&gt;perfect timelines and facts&lt;/a&gt; that the opposing party, not Russia, pulled the trigger? How many Retweets would a tweet get with fake evidence that Khrushchev had ordered the hit?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Popular sentiment is only one side of the coin, the demand side. Distribution also impacts who gets elected, the supply side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No book has shaped my thinking on modern politics more than Amusing Ourselves to Death. The author Neil Postman posits the first fifteen Presidents could have walked past most Americans and they wouldn’t be recognized. However, through their writing — their positions and arguments, those same oblivious Americans on the street would recognize the President they had just passed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the primary mode of communication was writing, passion was subservient to reason. That’s because in contrast to speaking, writing provides a natural buffer between what one is thinking and what one says; that buffer is time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing is not the transmission of linear thought. It can be amended between the ears, changed on paper, or erased all together before being transmitted to an audience. In turn this means the audience is now chewing on ideas in their very best form. There is context and nuance, opposed to a sound bite resulting from in the moment thinking or an out of context clip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve regressed from this dynamic form of thought transmission into a purely linear one. Even radio offered a larger buffer between thought and speech than does TV. A long pause in radio may have listeners instinctively glancing at their receiver to see if the feed cut out, but that pause costs the speaker almost nothing yet he gains the ability to collect his thoughts. On TV this pause would result in at best a slight cringe from viewers as they may see it as awkward, at worst the speaker is made subject of the next viral clip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The incentive to think before speaking is removed in lieu of a polished visual delivery. Roger Ailes would turn the volume off when judging the quality of his shows on Fox, knowing the language of TV is that of the body not mind. Which raises the question, isn’t the mark of humanity, the intelligent consciousness that separates us from the rest of the animal kingdom, the ability to reason?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The founders sure thought so. Federalist Nos: 6, 10, 15, 24, 41, 49, 50, 55, 63, 71, 73 all point to the vice of passion prevailing over the virtue of reason as a threat to the republic. Which they mediated with the structure of the Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In arguably the most important of the Federalist Papers, No.10, Pubilus warns “As long as the connection subsists between his reason and his self-love, his opinions and his passions will have a reciprocal influence on each other; and the former will be objects to which the latter will attach themselves”. Meaning opinions are often a product of passion, not reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Federalist 49, Madison rebukes Jefferson’s proposition of frequent constitutional conventions because of “The danger of disturbing the public tranquillity by interesting too strongly the public passions.” He goes on to codify his argument (emphasis his), “The PASSIONS, therefore, not the REASON, of the public would sit in judgment. But it is the reason, alone, of the public, that ought to control and regulate the government. The passions ought to be controlled and regulated by the government.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In making the case for a smaller number of House members in Federalist 55, Pubilus states “In all very numerous assemblies, of whatever characters composed, passion never fails to wrest the sceptre from reason. Had every Athenian citizen been a Socrates; every Athenian assembly would still have been a mob.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no question of the intent of the Framers, they sought to curb momentary political passions to make way for reason. While they may have structured the Constitution in such a way to do that when slow communications was the norm, they didn’t predict communications could traverse time and space instantaneously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Federalist 68, arguing the merits of the electoral college, Hamilton assures us “Talents for low intrigue, and the little arts of popularity, may alone suffice to elevate a man to the first honors in a single State; but it will require other talents, and a different kind of merit, to establish him in the esteem and confidence of the whole Union”. The subtext, when taking into account today’s political landscape, is clear — appeals to cheap passion opposed to sound reasoning may spell success in a single state, but such shallow footing would be washed away once the whole country could play judge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an argument hiding in plain sight about the virtues of democracy and republicanism, but for the purposes of this essay the missing ingredient is clear: the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first century of the country’s existence, it would have been impossible to reach the entire nation at the same time. The mechanics of campaigning at a national level still meant stitching together constituencies that lay upstream of communities. Since we began watching our politics, not only did regional appeals all but evaporate, our politicians shaped the contours of their messages to that medium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It began with TV. What did playing the saxophone or throwing a baseball have to do with parking two aircraft carrier battle groups in the Taiwan Strait or deciding to spend $700 billion on complicated mortgage securities from Wall Street?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our system began by running through gatekeepers, you had to work rigidly within the system to get elected. This was followed by newspaper politicians, split into 3 distinct eras. The party organ papers, the penny press era, and the objective era. The radio era didn’t last long but coupled with newspapers, America didn’t really start to erase the buffer with which politics was created and consumed until the TV era.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then came the internet era… in which reason has given way to passion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;//&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Founders set up our Constitutional Republic not to temper the passions of the people but to create a buffer between those passions and the laws that were made. They knew this was only human nature. To repeat Madison, “Had every Athenian citizen been a Socrates; every Athenian assembly would still have been a mob.” Think about what you would tell your best friend who is mad at someone and is about to make an impulse decision of retaliation. “Calm down, take a deep breath, give yourself some time to cool off before doing anything you might regret.” Humans in groups are no different, in fact they’re worse — as each person is feeding off the person next to them instead of acting as the voice of reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internet offers no such buffer. Our social distribution pipes are quite literally engineered to embolden the man besieged by passion. See something emotion provoking, take no time to process, eschew the search for context, type out your feelings straight from thinking, and allow yourself to translate the 1s&amp;amp;0s (masquerading as what your brain mistakes as affection) into dopamine. Repeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is one thing to take away from this essay, it’s that that feedback loop isn’t just driving neighbors apart — it’s setting the framework for our politicians to shape their messaging to. And to go a step further, the incentives within that framework naturally select who will succeed. The most boring yet brilliant medical policy professional won’t have a chance against a young fiery activist who knows nothing about the depths of medicine besides simple platitudes that the internet decodes into dopamine. While the former professional put primary voters to sleep. The consequence of dopamine? Distribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;//&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The speed of distribution matters. We have all heard of the canonical 24 hour news cycle, what is spoken of less is what used to occur in the 23 hours between the newspapers getting dropped off (or between evening newscasts). Those 23 hours were when people had time to digest what they had read in that morning’s paper. During those hours was when passion was converted to reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concurrently even if the impulses to respond via action were not tempered, there existed an additional gate of reason beyond the thought formulated in one’s head — physical distribution in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the democratization of media and the fall of gatekeeping is an unquestionable good in the abstract. In practice, there were tremendous benefits to having honest and studied actors filter political opinion. But in principle, the old system to decide whose opinion was heard, was simply who had the capital to finance the existing technologies for communicating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the physical buffer of distribution is entirely removed. The 280 character text box, and those like it, have created the link from mind to output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the recent primary upsets and subsequent rise of the victors is entirely a result of distribution. Their ability to find product market fit was dependent upon distribution. At first glance readers may nod their heads in agreement, understanding that social media allowed for going around gatekeepers with an unorthodox message. With the ability to reach specific individuals rather than a wide audience. Consequently getting those individuals who are uniquely passionate to share the candidate’s message to like minded voters. But it’s not that simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compared to elections past, it’s remarkably easy to get a campaign off the ground. You can build a website and build name ID with little up front cost and without the trappings of legacy gatekeepers. Conventional wisdom states that because the upfront costs were higher in the old days, campaigns should cost much less now. After all, you had to make physical flyers and purchase general purpose TV or newspaper advertising just to get started. Although, paradoxically, the cost of each campaign has grown dramatically in the internet era.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In large part, this is because it’s so easy to get name ID. One viral tweet and a non-trivial number of primary voters now not only know your name, they’re following your every thought. This has increased demand in terms of new politicians running for office, which has in turn driven up prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, with increasing demand and increasing prices, new players have swept onto the scene to build the campaign infrastructure that can scale up to match that demand. Along with the influx of citizens voicing their opinions, so too have they opened their checkbooks. Small dollar contributions have exploded over the past decade as each party has built the capability to convert that dopamine to dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 2010 cycle then House Speaker Nancy Pelosi raised a total of $1 million from individuals, and only $67k from small dollar donors (less than $200). In 2020, with two quarters left to report, she has raised over $11 million from individuals, $7.6 million from small dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the influx of cash is upstream from the real change in our politics, the politicians. 3 of the top 10 House members as of 6/30/20, are freshmen. 6 of the next 10 are freshman, 2 more are sophomores. In a world of analog distribution, fundraising moved at the speed of atoms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paradigm is still in its early stages, on the surface aligning voters and funding seems like a good thing. But one can only wonder about a time in the near future when we stop and ask — is it a good thing that normal people are draining their wallets in a never ending game of political musical chairs?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost certainly a super majority of these contributions are coming from passion, not reason. If you haven’t seen a campaign fundraising email, I envy you. Broken HTML, red text with yellow highlighting, and all caps slogans blasting the other side in digital shrieks of fatalism. Followed by 5, no 10, buttons to contribute. And now they send text messages! Somehow both Trump and Biden have texted me personally asking for money, at least that’s what it says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1966 California state treasurer Jesse “Big Daddy” Unruh said “Money is the mother’s milk of politics.” Indeed it is. And the spoils will go to those who can get it, no matter how it’s distributed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used to hire legislators, now we hire advocates. In the 18th and 19th centuries, and well into the 20th century, our elected representatives retained hardly any staff — they did the work themselves. They knew how to legislate, they knew how to govern. Now, so long as one can reach an online audience (usually with the help of Fox &amp;amp; MSNBC) and raise money, the real action can be farmed out to the agencies and no one will know the difference. So we’re told.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with that structure is that the advocates so often appeal to the people who have the power to keep them in their advocating position, sidestepping the odd fact that they were elected to achieve whatever they’re advocating for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t to say there aren’t tremendous legislators and governors, nor that any elected member that leverages internet distribution isn’t those things. It is to say that this is becoming the rule, so long as our political activities are distributed via the current schema of the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internet distribution gives us internet politicians and internet policies. The increasing political polarization and primary phenomenon on both left and right is much less a product of ideology as it is distribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not just the internet, TV isn’t done leaving its mark. There can be no debate that the seriousness and efficacy of Congressional Committees would be elevated exponentially if cameras were removed and replaced with transcripts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to believe there was once a time in which Presidents secretly operated newspapers from the White House, and that they were chastised for failing to buffer their thoughts through Congress on their way to the American people. Yet they would almost assuredly agree that public discourse through 10 second “stories” on Instagram is harebrained to say the least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is no coincidence that our politics takes the shape of distribution. When Americans learned of their candidates through 4 hour long debates as they did with Lincoln &amp;amp; Douglas, we were rewarded with Lincoln and Douglass caliber leaders. When we learn of our candidates through Twitter and Instagram, we get leaders that live up to the epistemological potential of those mediums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both sides of the electoral equation, supply and demand — politicians and voters, have started to lose the ability to reason in the internet age. As of 2020, we have made no constitutive choices as to how the internet may act as a distribution channel. We have no fairness doctrine for debate, as hyperbolic reactionaries dominate our digital airwaves. We have no limits on small dollars as elections balloon in cost with no end in sight. We have yet to think through the buffers that long safeguarded the republic. Perhaps we can’t, because there’s no buffer allowing us to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/share?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; class=&quot;twitter-share-button&quot; data-show-count=&quot;false&quot;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Essays" /><summary type="html">During Jackon’s Bank War in 1834, John Calhoun rose to the Senate floor to lament the fact Andrew Jackson had printed his own remarks to his Cabinet in Jackon’s newspaper the Washington Globe. Calhoun decried this as an exercise of despotic power, saying it “was clearly and manifestly intended as an appeal to the people of the United States, and opens a new and direct organ of communication between the President and them unknown to the Constitution and the laws…There are but two channels…through which the President can communicate with the people — by messages to the Two Houses of Congress…or by Proclamation.”</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/now-buffering.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/now-buffering.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">AMERICAN LION: Andrew Jackson in the White House</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/books/2020/09/14/jackson.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AMERICAN LION: Andrew Jackson in the White House" /><published>2020-09-14T11:41:39-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-14T11:41:39-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/books/2020/09/14/jackson</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/books/2020/09/14/jackson.html">&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/font-awesome/4.7.0/css/font-awesome.min.css&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight:500;font-style:italic;&quot;&gt; Author: Jon Meacham&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;margin-top:15px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight:500;&quot;&gt;tl;dr:&lt;/span&gt;Reading this book during the Trump Presidency is wild. There are so many similarities to how they structured their presidencies, and so many differences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Jackson’s time he was almost as revered in American military lore as Washington. He was the hero of New Orleans. Jackson parlayed this popularity into an electoral strategy, as he was the first President to derive his power from popular sentiment. His confidence and mandate to govern stemmed entirely from the people. So the real similarity is they were both populists. The difference being Jackson was, um, the hero of the War of 1812. And one of the best political theorists of his day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book itself is both great and bad, earning it a 3-star rating. Usually Pulitzer winners don’t miss but about 30% of the book was infuriatingly boring. The author obsesses over the Petticoat Affair, which was a social scandal that divided Washington in his first term. The tl;dr is that his Secretary of War, Eaton, married a woman (Mary) that was, shall we say, easy. The rest of the elite DC social circuit at the time refused to acknowledge her. He lays out why it was important but it was way overboard for high school drama.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bank war was the highlight of the book, the author could have expanded on that issue greatly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;&lt;b&gt;Stars: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;fa fa-star checked&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;fa fa-star checked&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;fa fa-star checked&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;fa fa-star&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;fa fa-star&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amazon: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/AMERICAN-LION-Andrew-Jackson-White/dp/0812973461&quot;&gt;AMERICAN LION: Andrew Jackson in the White House&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Books" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Link to Bessemer Venture Partners Investment Memos</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/pdfs/2020/09/12/BVP.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Link to Bessemer Venture Partners Investment Memos" /><published>2020-09-12T11:41:39-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-12T11:41:39-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/pdfs/2020/09/12/BVP</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/pdfs/2020/09/12/BVP.html">&lt;div style=&quot;margin-top:15px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bvp.com/memos&quot;&gt;Link to Memos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-bottom:30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="PDFs" /><category term="Business" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">This Insight on Coffee Changed my Life</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/notes/2020/08/09/coffee-insight.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="This Insight on Coffee Changed my Life" /><published>2020-08-09T11:41:39-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-09T11:41:39-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/notes/2020/08/09/coffee-insight</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/notes/2020/08/09/coffee-insight.html">&lt;p&gt;Aha! Got you to click. Well, hopefully it’s worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The the old coffee drinking me’s morning used to go something like this. Get up at around 5, slam a cup of coffee, get a workout in, be tired again by 8, then naturally drink another cup. Then, most days, I’d get ridiculously tired in the afternoon, and again after dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a hunch the timing of the first cup was likely to blame and sure enough, I found this handy graphic (don’t know source but the science checks out) and it changed the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/best_coffee_time.png&quot; alt=&quot;behold&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By drinking coffee before 9am you’re basically stopping for gas on a full tank, overflowing the tank, then causing most of the gas to spill out in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been drinking one cup around 9am and another around 2pm for almost two years now and it’s honestly revolutionary. There’s never a crash with this system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll admit, it’s not easy to go a few hours without a cup when I’m low on sleep. And converting coffee from an experience (like the smell as the sun is rising) to a utility kind of takes the pleasure out of it, but it’s worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Notes" /><summary type="html">Aha! Got you to click. Well, hopefully it’s worth it.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/best_coffee_time.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/best_coffee_time.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Fix Twitter, and Hopefully American Discourse Too</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/essays/2020/07/12/fix-twitter.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Fix Twitter, and Hopefully American Discourse Too" /><published>2020-07-12T09:01:39-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-12T09:01:39-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/essays/2020/07/12/fix-twitter</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/essays/2020/07/12/fix-twitter.html">&lt;p&gt;When I first joined Twitter in 2012, it was a great place to be. A lot of my friends were there, cracking jokes and posting pictures with yfrog while hoping the fail whale didn’t ruin the fun. I recall that the company was pitching Twitter as a “public agora”, which made sense but wasn’t an accurate reflection at that time. Really, it was juxtaposed against Facebook as a better social network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that Twitter &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; the public agora, its functionality defines the rules of engagement for public debate, and those rules allow for chaos and massacre. Twitter’s current functionality gravely endangers the future of the Republic. If they do not take it upon themselves to act now, they will be responsible for the American equivalent of moving the capital from St. Petersburg to Moscow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that sounds a little alarmist, because it is. However, Twitter can take a few steps to reverse their role in warehousing division and hate. As well as the mental health crisis that is outrage. “The medium is the message” has become trite, but Mcluhan’s point remains - Twitter needs to alter the medium before Americans succumb to the message. Here are a few ideas to do so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul style=&quot;margin-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Federate Twitter&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Hide Likes&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Reform the Quote Tweet&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Sentiment Analysis, Higher Quality &amp;amp; Lower Speed&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Tweet Wrapper =&amp;gt; Thread&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Clean Up Usernames&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;federate-twitter&quot;&gt;Federate Twitter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most audacious ask. People already use terms like “baseball Twitter” or “VC Twitter” as if they were clearly federated channels - why not actually do that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong, the aggregation of all my interests into one feed is amazing (and why no one visits news sites anymore), but in practice the intended effect hardly occurs. Usually my feed is plagued with the story of the day as if I’m turning on cable news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, it’s possible to tune it out sometimes, but that comes at the expense of missing out on other great content. I don’t want to follow Brian Koppelman or Buster Olney for their political takes, even if I agree with them 100%, I want to learn about storytelling and get updates on baseball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deescalating&lt;/strong&gt; the politicization of &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;, and reducing the speed at which takes come flying through the Twittersphere, will turn down the temperature and volume while providing for deeper engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way to do this would be to require users to tag the vertical(s) they want to post in before posting. &lt;strong&gt;The follower would then see the tweet only if they follow both the person and the vertical.&lt;/strong&gt; Users would be able to follow all of someone’s tweets if they want, but it would require one extra step - as the default follow functionality would result in only seeing the nexus of that person’s tweets and your follow tags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users would still be able to tweet without specific channels tagged. Only followers selecting all tweets or just personal (non-vertical) tweets would see them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of defining verticals, Twitter can do most of the leg work - defining the official taxonomy with layups like Football &amp;gt; NFL &amp;gt; Cleveland Browns. And with multiple entry points like Tech / Money / Cryptography &amp;gt; Cryptocurrencies &amp;gt; Bitcoin. There are easily thousands that can be defined (Topics is a far cry from what could be). Then figure out how to allow users to define new categories, maybe put the blue check to good use!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The upshot? &lt;strong&gt;This would also be a great business decision.&lt;/strong&gt; Twitter’s Q1 2020 CPM was $4.97. If they were to fully embrace contextual advertising, leveraging their first-party data as well, they could own a burgeoning segment of the digital ad market and raise their avg CPM well into double digits. Think about it, has a Twitter ad ever actually made an impact on you? Contextual is the natural response to the death of the cookie, most competition in this space won’t have the first party data nor the free inventory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hide-likes&quot;&gt;Hide Likes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make likes only visible to both the liker and likee. Twitter is optimized for virtue signalling, period. We’ve all read how tribal Twitter is, well this single feature is the forcing function of that tribalism in every last vertical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By making likes private, Twitter can still use the signal to optimize the home feed algo. In fact this will provide a much richer signal as the likes become a more honest indication of someone’s opinions, while preserving the personal satisfaction (dopamine) users get from likes. I’d wager this would make engagement go &lt;em&gt;up&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about the ability to scan someone else’s likes? Maybe this is where a new Quote Tweet comes in. A separate feed created by users that allows them to syndicate tweets without the full endorsement of a Retweet or the aforementioned problems of a like. No footprint on the tweet object itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reform-the-quote-tweet&quot;&gt;Reform the Quote Tweet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April, 6 2015 the Quote Tweet was born. I do not believe it an accident that, at least anecdotally, the culture of outrage and personal attack has grown exponentially on Twitter in the last 5 years. “Dunking” on someone seems to be the primary use of the Quote Tweet feature, and so many of the viral outrage tweets are in the form of the Quote Tweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, users were hacking this together before it happened so it’s obviously a popular feature. It makes sense; syndicating information is the primary purpose of Twitter - whether that’s from your brain or another source, everyone’s just a router. But the madness must stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;padding-bottom:0px; margin-bottom:-.5em;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Solutions&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add permissions on any tweet that gets Quote Tweeted:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;If a user comes by my tweet via a Quote Tweet, allow me to block them from viewing my  tweet via the Quote Tweet&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Allow me to set max absolute Quote Tweets or max Retweet of a subsequent Quote Tweet&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Allow me to disable Quote Tweets all together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OR, drum roll please… &lt;em&gt;edit button&lt;/em&gt;! It would solve so much. Then add a versionsioning system to allow the original to be preserved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Federation will actually solve this, but without it, these solutions are necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sentiment-analysis-higher-quality--lower-speed&quot;&gt;Sentiment Analysis, Higher Quality &amp;amp; Lower Speed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the questions raised by the federation idea is, what happens to generally public features like Trends? Twitter as a resource for breaking news can’t be disputed at this point; that functionality must be preserved and strengthened. But the current set up just aint it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are two tweets taken from two recent trends, ‘Susan Collins’ and ‘Nancy Pelosi’ respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet tw-align-center&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;F*ck Trump&lt;br /&gt;F*ck Barr&lt;br /&gt;F*ck Lindsey Graham&lt;br /&gt;F*ck Mitch McConnell&lt;br /&gt;F*ck Susan Collins&lt;br /&gt;F*ck Ted Cruz&lt;br /&gt;F*ck John Cornyn&lt;br /&gt;F*ck Tom Cotton&lt;br /&gt;F*ck Cory Gardner&lt;br /&gt;F*ck Chuck Grassley&lt;br /&gt;F*ck John Kennedy&lt;br /&gt;F*ck Matt Gaetz&lt;br /&gt;F*ck Jim Jordan&lt;br /&gt;F*ck Kelly Loeffler&lt;br /&gt;F*ck Rand Paul&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;F*CK THE ENTIRE GOP &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/PR0KyoE5K8&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/PR0KyoE5K8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; José (@yoruguaenusa) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yoruguaenusa/status/1281774758967889921?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;July 11, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet tw-align-center&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;⁦&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JoeBiden?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@JoeBiden&lt;/a&gt;⁩ ⁦&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SpeakerPelosi?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@SpeakerPelosi&lt;/a&gt;⁩ Sums it well &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/OnsAyce9Mp&quot;&gt;https://t.co/OnsAyce9Mp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; nicole (@nicole47877716) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nicole47877716/status/1281977304567222274?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;July 11, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both of these were less than 20 tweets into the “Top” section that is ostensibly a filter of quality compared to the “Latest” option. Twitter has to stop this type of hyperbolic outrage, and nonsensical filler. Those tweets are of no value to anyone (not to mention, inciting violence?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If those same accounts wanted to make reasoned and informed arguments against those politicians, by all means. Even if the arguments are far outside the Overton window, so long as they are thoughtful they should be surfaced equally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sentiment analysis, scoring primarily thoughtfulness, can raise the quality bar. Modern advances in NLP should make this not only possible but possible to do well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, sentiment analysis should be used to grade tweets that begin to go viral. Auto-braking tweets at certain Retweet and reply counts could be detrimental when serious breaking news occurs, so that will have to be a consideration. But scoring the sentiment to make sure it’s not vitriolic outrage based in emotion could lower the speed of hate and reduce the collective blood pressure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a general rule of thumb, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lindy_effect&quot;&gt;Lindy effect&lt;/a&gt; should be the governing principle. If you cap Retweets and replies in absolute numbers or by sentiment, and the content is actually good enough, it will continue to rise to the top over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tweet-wrapper--thread&quot;&gt;Tweet Wrapper =&amp;gt; Thread&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Threads are awesome, but there’s a reason services like unroll exist. Reading a thread interrupted by the username, picture, etc. every 280 characters is taxing. Secondly, syndication of a tweet in a thread can lose all context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;padding-bottom:0px; margin-bottom:-.5em;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Solution&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Convert the thread into a single object segmented by 280 character fields, separated either by nothing or slightly darker/lighter backgrounds. The reader sees breaks every 280 characters like normal, but it’s much cleaner and more importantly - will convey a sense of coherence. The world is an incredibly nuanced place. Discourse in 280 characters is not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user can then choose which tweet in the thread serves as a wrapper. And/or when Retweeted, that user can choose which tweet will serve as the wrapper. The wrapper is more or less a headline - when the user clicks on the wrapper tweet, they move to the seamless thread.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This solution has the additional benefit of synchronizing replies onto a single thread object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;clean-up-usernames&quot;&gt;Clean Up Usernames&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much of the nonsensical outrage comes from usernames like ‘jack09324189’. The username from the Pelosi example above is ‘nicole47877716’, and the account is following 5 people with one follower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m against a strict real name policy - but Twitter can also make a constitutive choice that bifurcates users into real names and pseudonyms. If you’re going to use a real name - great, you must have a real profile. If you want to be anonymous - great, you must set up a truly pseudonymous account. The strangle between the two is what accounts for most of the filler in replies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook is obviously a bit draconian with their policy, &lt;em&gt;but at least they have one&lt;/em&gt;. If Twitter is to be the public agora, it must build the mechanisms with which discourse worthy of that title can flourish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, replies need to be fixed but I don’t really have a solution. Federation and cleaning up usernames would absolutely help, but don’t constitute a silver bullet. Having 5k replies on a tweet is pure insanity, as most of those replies prove. Would love to hear ideas here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it’s fair to say Twitter (the company) subscribes to the theory of stakeholder capitalism. If there is any stakeholder of Twitter worth protecting, it is Western civilization. Designing the product with this in mind is the only way to add civility and nuance on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditionally we’ve regulated the means of communication that carry political messaging, but the digital frontier is a brave new world, we don’t know how to regulate it. I’d be remiss if I said I thought regulators could solve the problem. Though parallels exist, we force auto manufacturers to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.law.cornell.edu/cfr/text/49/393.40&quot;&gt;add brakes&lt;/a&gt;, and we tax cigarettes because they’re bad for us. Twitter needs brakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s incumbent on leaders inside Twitter to lead. Take the reins and implement changes that will benefit society writ large. There need not be some blue ribbon commission, some special committee, no DC panels, a long study, or a non-profit dedicated to some ethics in tech. We need action. Yesterday. Great things happen &lt;a href=&quot;https://patrickcollison.com/fast&quot;&gt;fast&lt;/a&gt;. Twitter only needs to do the right thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/share?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot; class=&quot;twitter-share-button&quot; data-show-count=&quot;false&quot;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Essays" /><summary type="html">When I first joined Twitter in 2012, it was a great place to be. A lot of my friends were there, cracking jokes and posting pictures with yfrog while hoping the fail whale didn’t ruin the fun. I recall that the company was pitching Twitter as a “public agora”, which made sense but wasn’t an accurate reflection at that time. Really, it was juxtaposed against Facebook as a better social network.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/twit_post.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/twit_post.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Freedom of the Press Isn’t About Journalism, It’s About People</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/notes/2020/07/07/press-freedom.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Freedom of the Press Isn't About Journalism, It's About People" /><published>2020-07-07T11:41:39-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-07T11:41:39-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/notes/2020/07/07/press-freedom</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/notes/2020/07/07/press-freedom.html">&lt;p&gt;When facing criticism, a common rebuke used by the Press is that the accuser is attacking “a free press”. The operative word being ‘free’. What that criticism often is - pointing out inaccuracies, or items that are not fair to the subject - is entirely removed from the argument at hand, the freedom to publish. In fact, one can argue that the First Amendment’s clause citing a free press has just as much, if not more, to do with the critic’s freedom as the original publisher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Journalists love this quote from Jefferson about free and fair press, &lt;em&gt;“were it left to me to decide whether we should have a government without newspapers or newspapers without a government, I should not hesitate a moment to prefer the latter.”&lt;/em&gt; I couldn’t agree more. But there are two huge problems with the contemporary use of the quote and similar lines of reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, ‘newspapers’ in 1789 were not a distribution vehicle for the then-not-invented concept of 20th century journalism. Second, Jefferson wrote a litany of letters sharply critical of the Press, mostly from his later and post Presidency years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reporting as we think of it now was still far away. If those early newspapers did contain what we think of as contemporary news, it was almost always either reports from Europe that were sometimes months old or local news of a town’s doings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With newfound access to the debates of Parliament, the act of reporting blossomed in late 18th century London. But, according to Mitchell Stephens’ &lt;em&gt;History of News&lt;/em&gt;, it was not until the 1820s that it came to America. 1822 was the first year a reporter from outside Washington took up covering DC. And it wasn’t until almost 20 years later with the advent of the telegraph that, as Neil Postman puts it, ‘we had decontextualized news of the day’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Impartiality, in the same flavor we’ve come to expect from our outlets, was alive in the early years of the Republic. There were high minded Federalist newspapers that sought impartiality, but they were not primarily gathering news, and quickly became the exception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Continental Congress and Original Colonies were not shy about the role they saw for the press in a new Union of States. In a 1774 address the Congress stated the freedom of the press promotes &lt;em&gt;“truth, science, morality….[and] whereby oppressive officers are shamed or intimidated into more honourable and just modes of conducting affairs.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Pennsylvania Declaration of rights stated &lt;em&gt;“The people have a right to freedom of speech, and of writing, and publishing their sentiments, therefore, the freedom of the press ought not to be restrained”&lt;/em&gt; That verbiage implies strong sentiment for absolute freedom, as well as no special treatment to publish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps most important in figuring out what was meant by ‘press freedom’ back then is how the two seminal cases regarding it set the tone for the issue in America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1733 John Peter Zenger, printer and publisher of &lt;em&gt;The New York Weekly Journal&lt;/em&gt; was arrested and imprisoned for eight months before surviving trial for criticizing the New York Royal Governor. His defense introduced an argument that would be used by future journalists accused of libel - truth. That it is not libelous if it is true. More importantly, the defense was adopted by the hearts and minds of American citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;69 years later Harry Croswell, the editor of an explicitly Federalist newspaper &lt;em&gt;The WASP&lt;/em&gt; (opposed to the Democratic-Republican paper &lt;em&gt;The Bee&lt;/em&gt;), was put on trial for asserting President Jefferson had paid James Callender to call George Washington “a traitor, a robber and a perjurer” as well as attacking John Adams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After losing the case, Alexander Hamilton rose to his defense in an appeal heard by the NY Supreme Court. He argued that truth is a defense for libel, and Justice James Kent essentially agreed. The case was lost but the spirit of Kent’s opinion was codified in NY State’s laws, followed by PA, and eventually the soul of the American people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Alien &amp;amp; Sedition Acts, and the Sedition Act of 1918, both jailed political figures for their writings, not the modern interpretation of objective journalists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point of these examples is that our modern interpretation of the First Amendment regarding the Press is actually a product of political discourse, not modern reporting. Reporting is certainly covered, but the precedents and sentiment that set that tone are a byproduct of individual actors and publications, not card carrying members of a press corps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the second point. Jefferson well understood the role of a free press in principle, but he also despised them in practice. He understood what is true today, humans pay attention to news that is grandiose. His entire quote, often reduced to &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.loc.gov/resource/mtj1.038_0592_0594/?sp=2&amp;amp;st=text&quot;&gt;“Nothing can now be believed which is seen in a newspaper”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is worth reading:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
“To your request of my opinion of the manner in which a newspaper should be conducted, so as to be most useful, I should answer, “by restraining it to true facts &amp;amp; sound principles only.” Yet I fear such a paper would find few subscribers. It is a melancholy truth, that a suppression of the press could not more compleatly deprive the nation of it's benefits, than is done by it's abandoned prostitution to falsehood. Nothing can now be believed which is seen in a newspaper. Truth itself becomes suspicious by being put into that polluted vehicle. The real extent of this state of misinformation is known only to those who are in situations to confront facts within their knowledge with the lies of the day. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I really look with commiseration over the great body of my fellow citizens, who, reading newspapers, live &amp;amp; die in the belief, that they have known something of what has been passing in the world in their time; whereas the accounts they have read in newspapers are just as true a history of any other period of the world as of the present, except that the real names of the day are affixed to their fables. General facts may indeed be collected from them, such as that Europe is now at war, that Bonaparte has been a successful warrior, that he has subjected a great portion of Europe to his will, &amp;amp;c., &amp;c.; but no details can be relied on. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I will add, that the man who never looks into a newspaper is better informed than he who reads them; inasmuch as he who knows nothing is nearer to truth than he whose mind is filled with falsehoods &amp;amp; errors. He who reads nothing will still learn the great facts, and the details are all false.”
&lt;br /&gt; - Thomas Jefferson to John Norvell, June 11, 1807&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The argument I make here is analogous, the importance of the freedom to publish cannot be understated. With that comes the right to critique what is being published.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to improve our society from the consequences of this Noble Myth, we must not limit the scope of press freedom, but expand it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about it this way. Anonymity is taking this example to its furthest extreme. Yet some of the most important writing to appear within the pages of a newspaper was written anonymously. The Federalist Papers and the Anti-Federalist Papers, which carried the weight of selling 13 states on banding together, were written under pseudonyms! Ben Franklin was famous for writing anonymously under pen names such as Silence Dogood, Richard Saunders, and Busy Body. How did this era of anonymous, non-journalistic, era of information turn out? I’d say we did alright.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s time to apply the same level of press freedom in practice to everyone, both in praise and critique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:10px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Adapted from my Essay: &lt;a href=&quot;https://jfeiwell.com/essays/2020/05/10/narrative-distribution-monopoly.html&quot;&gt;The Narrative Distribution Monopoly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Journalists love this quote from Jefferson about free and fair press, &lt;em&gt;“were it left to me to decide whether we should have a government without newspapers or newspapers without a government, I should not hesitate a moment to prefer the latter.”&lt;/em&gt; I couldn’t agree more. But there are two huge problems with the contemporary use of the quote and similar lines of reasoning, as they butcher Jefferson’s intent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, ‘newspapers’ in 1789 were not a distribution vehicle for the then-not-invented concept of 20th century journalism. Second, Jefferson wrote a litany of letters sharply critical of the press, mostly from his later and post Presidency years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reporting as we think of it now was still far away. If those early newspapers did contain what we think of as modern news, it was almost always either reports from Europe that were sometimes months old or local news of a town’s doings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With newfound access to the debates of Parliament, the act of reporting blossomed in late 18th century London. But, according to Mitchell Stephens’ &lt;em&gt;History of News&lt;/em&gt;, it was not until the 1820s until it came to America. 1822 was the first year a reporter from outside Washington took up covering DC. And it wasn’t until almost 20 years later with the advent of the telegraph that, as Neil Postman puts it, ‘we had decontextualized news of the day’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Impartiality, in the same flavor we’ve come to expect from our outlets, was alive in the early years of the Republic. There were high minded Federalist newspapers that sought impartiality, but they were not primarily gathering news, and quickly became the exception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deliberately, the Continental Congress and Original Colonies were not shy about the role they saw for the press in a new Union of States. In a 1774 address the Congress stated the freedom of the press promotes &lt;em&gt;“truth, science, morality….[and] whereby oppressive officers are shamed or intimidated into more honourable and just modes of conducting affairs.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Pennsylvania Declaration of rights stated &lt;em&gt;“The people have a right to freedom of speech, and of writing, and publishing their sentiments, therefore, the freedom of the press ought not to be restrained”&lt;/em&gt; That verbiage implies strong sentiment for absolute freedom, as well as no special treatment to publish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps most important in figuring out what was meant by ‘press freedom’ back then is how the two seminal cases set the tone for the issue in America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1733 John Peter Zenger, printer and publisher of &lt;em&gt;The New York Weekly Journal&lt;/em&gt; was arrested and imprisoned for eight months before surviving trial for criticizing the New York Royal Governor. His defense introduced an argument that would be used by future journalists accused of libel - truth. That it is not libelous if it is true. More importantly, the defense was adopted by the hearts and minds of American citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;69 years later Harry Croswell, the editor of an explicitly Federalist newspaper &lt;em&gt;The WASP&lt;/em&gt; (opposed to the Democratic-Republican paper &lt;em&gt;The Bee&lt;/em&gt;), was put on trial for asserting President Jefferson had paid James Callender to call George Washington “a traitor, a robber and a perjurer” as well as attacking John Adams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After losing the case, Alexander Hamilton rose to his defense in an appeal heard by the NY Supreme Court. He argued that truth is a defense for libel, and Justice James Kent essentially agreed. The case was lost but the spirit of Kent’s opinion was codified in NY State’s laws, followed by PA, and eventually the soul of the American people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This not to mention the Alien &amp;amp; Sedition Acts or the Sedition Act of 1918, both jailing political figures, not the modern interpretation of objective journalists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point of these examples is that our modern interpretation of the First Amendment regarding the press is actually a product of political discourse, not modern reporting. Reporting is certainly covered, but the precedents and sentiment that set that tone are a byproduct of individual actors and publications, not card carrying members of a press corps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the second point. Jefferson well understood the role of a free press in principle, but he also despised them in practice. He understood what is true today, humans pay attention to news that is grandiose. His entire quote, often reduced to &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.loc.gov/resource/mtj1.038_0592_0594/?sp=2&amp;amp;st=text&quot;&gt;“Nothing can now be believed which is seen in a newspaper”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is worth reading:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
“To your request of my opinion of the manner in which a newspaper should be conducted, so as to be most useful, I should answer, “by restraining it to true facts &amp;amp; sound principles only.” Yet I fear such a paper would find few subscribers. It is a melancholy truth, that a suppression of the press could not more compleatly deprive the nation of it's benefits, than is done by it's abandoned prostitution to falsehood. Nothing can now be believed which is seen in a newspaper. Truth itself becomes suspicious by being put into that polluted vehicle. The real extent of this state of misinformation is known only to those who are in situations to confront facts within their knowledge with the lies of the day. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I really look with commiseration over the great body of my fellow citizens, who, reading newspapers, live &amp;amp; die in the belief, that they have known something of what has been passing in the world in their time; whereas the accounts they have read in newspapers are just as true a history of any other period of the world as of the present, except that the real names of the day are affixed to their fables. General facts may indeed be collected from them, such as that Europe is now at war, that Bonaparte has been a successful warrior, that he has subjected a great portion of Europe to his will, &amp;amp;c., &amp;c.; but no details can be relied on. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I will add, that the man who never looks into a newspaper is better informed than he who reads them; inasmuch as he who knows nothing is nearer to truth than he whose mind is filled with falsehoods &amp;amp; errors. He who reads nothing will still learn the great facts, and the details are all false.”
&lt;br /&gt; - Thomas Jefferson to John Norvell, June 11, 1807&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The argument I make here is analogous, the importance of the freedom to publish cannot be understated. With that comes the right to critique what is being published.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to improve our society from the consequences of this Noble Myth I want to hammer home the point here. &lt;strong&gt;It is not to limit our interpretation of the scope of press freedom, but rather to expand it&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about it this way. Anonymity is taking this example to its furthest extreme. Yet some of the most important writing to appear within the pages of a newspaper was written anonymously. The Federalist Papers and the Anti-Federalist Papers, which carried the weight of selling a collection of 13 states into forming a Union, were written under pseudonyms! Ben Franklin was famous for writing anonymously under pen names such as Silence Dogood, Richard Saunders, and Busy Body. I posit, how did this era of anonymous, non-journalistic, era of information turn out? I’d say we did alright.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s time to apply the same level of press freedom in practice to everyone, both in praise and critique.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Notes" /><summary type="html">When facing criticism, a common rebuke used by the Press is that the accuser is attacking “a free press”. The operative word being ‘free’. What that criticism often is - pointing out inaccuracies, or items that are not fair to the subject - is entirely removed from the argument at hand, the freedom to publish. In fact, one can argue that the First Amendment’s clause citing a free press has just as much, if not more, to do with the critic’s freedom as the original publisher.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/press.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/press.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The ABC Universal Commercial Electric Telegraphic Code</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/pdfs/2020/07/01/abcuniversal.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The ABC Universal Commercial Electric Telegraphic Code" /><published>2020-07-01T11:41:39-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-01T11:41:39-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/pdfs/2020/07/01/abcuniversal</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/pdfs/2020/07/01/abcuniversal.html">&lt;div style=&quot;margin-top:15px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight:500;&quot;&gt;tl;dr:&lt;/span&gt; Probably the best resource for naming a company or project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telegrams were pithy, using literal convections with few to no punctuations. Telegram services like Western Union used to charge by the word and even character limit words, so different sets of codes were developed to convey more meaning in fewer words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guide takes a root word, lists common phrases using that word, and assigns a word as a code for the phrase. Many of the code words are unique, which is what makes this a powerful naming tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;
&quot;Every day the value of the telegraphic system is being more and more
felt. It has revolutionised our commerce, and proved of inestimable value in domestic affairs ; there is no relation of life in which the in- fluence of the change it has effected has not been felt. Electricity has done as much as human effort can accomplish towards the annihilation of space and time, and its adaptation for practical purposes is, perhaps,
the greatest invention of the present century.&quot;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Author: William Clauson-Thue&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/pdfs/abcuniversal.pdf&quot;&gt;The ABC Universal Commercial Electric Telegraphic Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-bottom:30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="PDFs" /><category term="Business" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>